<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<!--
    SPDX-License-Identifier: GPL-3.0-or-later
    NG-native changelog. Used by ChangelogActivity / ChangelogParser.
    DOCTYPE is intentionally omitted: XmlPullParser does not validate against a DTD
    and the upstream-hosted DTD URL must not be fetched at runtime.
-->
<changelog>
    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v0.4.2"
        code="6"
        date="13 May 2026">
        <note>Premium polish release focused on trust, clarity, and feedback.</note>
        <improve title="First run">Refined first-run security handoff, calmer recovery-password copy, and stronger trust panel.</improve>
        <improve title="Notifications">Contextual Android 13+ notification asks for wireless ADB pairing, batch operations, and installer progress.</improve>
        <improve title="Premium polish">Normalized Material shape language across chips, popups, bottom sheets, onboarding, widgets, and shared cards. Softened warning surfaces.</improve>
        <improve title="Updates">Build-expiry copy and update links now point to the AppManagerNG release / actions channels.</improve>
        <fix title="Security">Hardened the `app-manager://` and `am://` deep-link parser against crash and validation-bypass; defused CSV / formula injection in operation-history exports.</fix>
        <fix title="Security">Locked down static launcher shortcuts behind a trampoline so installed apps cannot smuggle destructive batch-op extras.</fix>
        <fix title="Locale">Per-app locale picker now reconciles bidirectionally with the Android 13+ system Language surface.</fix>
    </release>

    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v0.4.1"
        code="5"
        date="8 May 2026">
        <note>Maintenance release closing 19 Now / Eng-Debt rows from the iter-19 / iter-20 drains.</note>
        <new title="Distribution">Reproducible release pipeline: two clean builds, SHA-256 compare, per-APK sidecars.</new>
        <new title="CI">Dependency CVE scan workflow with PR Dependency Review + weekly OWASP Dependency Check.</new>
        <new title="CI">Upstream repo-rename watcher opens an audit issue if the upstream slug ever drifts.</new>
        <new title="Distribution">Static launcher shortcuts for 1-Click Ops, Running Apps, and Finder.</new>
        <new title="Locale">`am://app/[pkg]` short alias for `app-manager://details?id=[pkg]` plus the documented intent API at docs/intent-api.md.</new>
        <improve title="Locale">Pseudolocale resources (en-XA / en-XB) on debug builds for truncation and RTL stress.</improve>
        <improve title="Crypto">BouncyCastle 1.83 -> 1.84 closes CVE-2026-3505 / 5588 / 5598.</improve>
        <note subtext="true">
            Known issue: multi-file AES-encrypted backups produced by v0.4.0 and v0.4.1 reuse the GCM IV across files
            and cannot be trusted to restore. OpenPGP / RSA / ECC and single-file AES backups are unaffected.
            See docs/audits/2026-05-08-gcm-cipher-reuse-large-backup.md.
        </note>
    </release>

    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v0.4.0"
        code="4"
        date="2 May 2026">
        <note>Discovery release: Permission Inspector + Onboarding capability wizard.</note>
        <new title="Permissions">Permission Inspector flips the per-app view on its head: pick a permission group and revoke across every installed app at once, with a critical-package guard.</new>
        <new title="Onboarding">Capability wizard detects root, Shizuku, ADB, KernelSU, APatch, Magisk, ZygiskNext, and the platform privileged shell, then explains the privilege path in plain language.</new>
        <new title="ADB">Guided Wireless ADB setup with persisted pairing metadata and ADB-over-TCP fallback.</new>
        <new title="Debloater">Privacy / Gaming / Minimal OEM presets with reviewed remove vs freeze confirmation.</new>
        <improve title="Adaptive layout">w600dp density overrides and Activity Embedding master/detail on >=900dp screens.</improve>
        <improve title="Android 16">Predictive back, themed icons, edge-to-edge, 16 KB native page-size alignment, elegantTextHeight audit clean.</improve>
        <improve title="Crypto">Per-file AES-GCM IV derivation (backup metadata v6) closes the multi-file IV reuse for new backups; legacy backups remain restorable.</improve>
    </release>

    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v0.3.0"
        code="3"
        date="5 June 2026">
        <note>UX refresh and platform compliance baseline.</note>
        <new title="Theme">Material 3 dashboard, Pro Mode toggle, AMOLED / dark / light themes.</new>
        <new title="Platform">Edge-to-edge enforcement and predictive back for Android 15 / 16.</new>
        <improve title="Security">Keystore passwords moved to `char[]` with explicit zeroing; ABX / XML round-trips preserve data losslessly.</improve>
        <improve title="Observability">Opt-in crash reporting, in-app diagnostic dump, CodeQL on main.</improve>
    </release>

    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v0.2.0"
        code="2"
        date="30 April 2026">
        <note>Identity release.</note>
        <improve title="Identity">applicationId renamed to `io.github.sysadmindoc.AppManagerNG` so AppManagerNG installs side-by-side with upstream.</improve>
        <improve title="Distribution">Fresh release keystore, GitHub Actions release pipeline, NG-specific CONTRIBUTING.md.</improve>
    </release>

    <release
        type="stable release"
        version="v0.1.0"
        code="1"
        date="30 April 2026">
        <note>Initial AppManagerNG bootstrap from upstream App Manager 4.0.5 (commit `3d11bcb`).</note>
        <note subtext="true">
            AppManagerNG is a continuation of [a href="https://github.com/MuntashirAkon/AppManager"]MuntashirAkon/AppManager[/a]
            under GPL-3.0-or-later. Upstream credit is preserved in the README Credits section.
        </note>
    </release>
</changelog>
